Matt, Matt, I've noticed British people
say sorry a lot.
>> Yeah, that's very true.
>> Even when it's not their fault.
>> Especially then.
>> So, why do people do that?
>> It helps keep the conversations polite
and friendly. It can be a polite way of
getting someone's attention or starting
a conversation.
>> Okay, so how could I ask someone for
directions?
>> You can start with a "Sorry to bother
you."
>> Oh, okay. Even though I'm not bothering.
>> Yeah, it just sounds polite.
>> Okay. And should I say thank you
afterwards?
>> Always. Even if they don't know the
answer.
>> Okay, so I say "Sorry to bother you."
and then I thank them. What if they
don't know the answer then?
>> You still thank them cuz you're still
bothering them a little bit. Then you
find someone else and ask them.
>> Okay, so I could say thank you anyways?
>> Yeah, definitely. You really should. So
much more polite.
>> I'll start practicing that.
>> Yeah, you got it. If you want to learn
more about British culture, one of my
most popular courses at the moment is
our UK culture course. That's because it
teaches English in a unique and fun way.
No trying to motivate yourself to use a
language learning app one more time.
This course will get you to be motivated
to turn up every week and actually learn
English without even realizing it.
That's because you're learning alongside
others in a structured way that also
suits your schedule and talk about
things that actually mean something to
someone, i.e. people in the UK. Learn
more at suzieblue.com/culture.
Comment culture down below for more
information.